Guide to the Garry Trudeau Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Garry Trudeau papers
1967-2017
YCAL MSS 747
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
110.71
(129 boxes)
The Garry Trudeau papers, spanning from 1967 to 2017, contain notebooks, research, correspondence, business papers, photographs, artwork, audiovisual materials, and writings. The papers also contain materials related to Garry Trudeau's work in theater and screen productions, several lines of merchandise, and various awards and recognitions.
Trudeau, G. B., 1948-
Trudeau, G. B., 1948- ( Doonesbury)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 49, 61-62, 67 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 31, 38 (electronic media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 58, 127 (record album storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 40-42, 36, 46, 63, 67 (videocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
October 2007 acquistion: gift of Garry Trudeau, 2007.
March 2018 acquisition: purchased from Doonesbury Ltd. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2018.
Garry Trudeau
Garry Trudeau was born in New York City in 1948, and was raised in Saranac Lake, New York. He received a B.A. and M.F.A. in graphic design from Yale University. In 1970, he launched the comic strip Doonesbury, which (as of 2007) appears in over one thousand newspapers worldwide. His work has also appeared in the form of books, films, and theater musicals.
Scope and Contents
The Garry Trudeau papers, spanning from 1967 to 2017, contain notebooks, research, correspondence, business papers, and artwork related to Doonesbury. The papers also contain materials related to Garry Trudeau's work in theater and screen productions, journalism, fan letters, merchandise, and awards.
Cartoonists -- United States -- Archives; Cartoons (humorous images); Political cartoons; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Cartoonists -- United States -- 20th Century; Trudeau, G. B., 1948-
- October 2007 acquisition, 1969-2007; 4.38; (11 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged in chronological order.
  Scope and Contents
  The October 2007 acquisition consists of forty-two notebooks, dating from 1969 to 2007, which contain notes and sketches documenting the creation of Doonesbury, other cartoons, and related work.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 986.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Garry Trudeau, 2007.
  - Notebooks, 1969-1973; 4 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 1973-1975; 4 (Box 2)
  - Notebooks, 1976-1977; 4 (Box 3)
  - Notebooks, 1978-1980; 5 (Box 4)
  - Notebooks, 1980-1985; 4 (Box 5)
  - Notebooks, 1985-1988; 4 (Box 6)
  - Notebooks, 1988-1993; 4 (Box 7)
  - Notebooks, 1994-1997; 4 (Box 8)
  - Notebooks, 1999-2001; 4 (Box 9)
  - Notebooks, 2002-2005; 4 (Box 10)
  - Notebooks, 2007 January (Box 11)